

Liyuan Dong Full Stack Developer

PROFILE

Address Keji 2nd Road XI'AN CHINA

Website https://happydongzh.github.io

Date Of Birth

24 November 1980

Github

https://happydongzh.github.io/learnFun/ LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/liyuan-dong-332528284

CERTIFICATIONS

Redhat	June 2017
RHCA Redhat	June 2017
OCJP Oracle	June 2014

LANGUAGES

English	Chinese
Fluent	Native Tongue

HOBBIES

Travelling

Table tennis

Riding, Reading

SUMMARY

As a full-stack developer, Liyuan offers strong skills in Javascript, java. he has extensive experience in commercial software development using various languages, platforms and technologies. He has worked in both front-end and back-end, but mainly in front-end recent

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM China(CP4D Datastage Xi'An)

Function Design / Lead / Developer

- (January 2020 Present)
- Discussion with global and domestic teams to analyses requirements.
- Analysis and assessed project scope, functional design, review and write design documents.
- Features/function task break down, schedule rough dev plan and assignment.
- As agile development team, hold daily scrum meeting to know the project/tasks progress, problems, issues and risks and make adjustment if need.
- Learn, investigate and research new tech or 3rd party library for project use if need.
- Create code skeleton structure to ensure the code is well organized. And common API/components design and implements.
- Features/functions coding and test.
- Issues fix, code review. Sometimes do code refactoring/optimize to ensure the performance at code level.

Tech Stack: Javascript, React, CSS, Java, Webservice, Docker.

IBM China (Platform App Center-LSF add-on)

(October 2010 - December 2019)

- Attend daily scrum meeting to report project progress, issues and risks.
- Discuss with team and UX designer to indicate and clarify the requirements.
- Provide prototype according to the UX design.
- Write functional design documents.
- Coding,E2E test and bug fix.
- L3(online customer support and solution).

Tech Stack: Java, JavaScrript, REST, Spring Boot, SpringMVC, MySQL, Linux, Shell Bash, VNC, Git.

Platform Computing

Senior Developer / L3

Web developer

(October 2008 - October 2020)

Web developer -Attend team meeting to review/discuss about function requirement. -Write test case doc. -Follow design doc to implements back-end and front-end GUI -Test and bug

Tech Stacks Struts 1/2, Hibernate, Java Servlet, Apache Tomcat, HTML, Javascript

Bomite Advertisement Shanghai

Java propgrammer

(July 2006 - August 2008)

Java programmer & tester

- Attend team meeting to review/discuss about function requirement.
- Write test case doc.
- Follow function design doc to implements the java function.
- Test and bug fix.

Tech Stack: Java, CVS, SQL Server.

EDUCATION

XI'AN Foreign University

Associate degree Computer Science & Engineering

(September 2001 - June 2004)

SKILLS

Javascript	React.js
5 Years	3 Years
Java	nodeJS
7 Years	2 Years
Linux	Docker
6 Years	1 Year
Git	SpringMVC
3 Years	3 Years
MySal/MariaDB	

MySql/MariaDB

5 Years

PROJECTS

DataStage - Hierarchical/Investigate Stage https://www.ibm.com/products/cloud-pak-for-data

(April 2020 - July 2023)

Develop investigate stage for cloud user to use the data flow to analysis the data or user could import the project files which contains the flow exported from legacy system(IBM Info Server).

Contribution:

- Learn investigate stage usage and use cases.
- Determine the requirements and function design.
- Summarize and break down tasks.
- Assign task to team.
- Build code skeleton and common widgets/API.
- Weekly demo to global team and follow up the comments from demo/review meeting, and make sure the comments is been addressed.
- Knowledge sharing and program language training for junior developer.

VNC Job Management / Job Files Purge (Platform App Center) (February 2019 - January 2020)

With LSF cluster management, user has different jobs running on different host with difference operating(hypervisor host) system, such as redhat, unbuntu, sues-linux, centOS etc. and end user need to view the job output files through the remote desktop, but there no way for user to open and manage the remote desktop sessions for related visualization job. Develop a GUI interface to let user manage his job remote desktop session.

The user job files and directories is auto purged as user configured schedule, but there is no way for user to debug, reset or analysis the job file purge schedule, develop a tool to reset and debug the purge schedule and related information.

Contribution:

- Learn and investigate linux remote desktop mechanism among different distortions.
- Determine the requirements, scope, function and provide UI prototype.
- Summarize and break down tasks and make project schedule/plan
- Write design document.
- Follow the design doc to implements the function.

•

• With agile methodologies, periodically provide the user scenario show case and prototype demo and review with team, L3 and customer, and get feedback for project development iterative and incremental. Timely adjustment, resolve conflicts of project tasks and schedule.